MOHAMMAD IMRAN HOSSAIN

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Email: imranhossain16.ctg@gmail.com Cell: +8801866803833

Github: https://github.com/imranctg16 Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/mohammad-imran-hossain-783803135/

SUMMARY

I'm Mohammad Imran Hossain, and I bring over five years of web development experience to the table. My focus lies in crafting user-friendly experiences, leveraging technologies like Amazon Web Services (AWS) and mastering microservices architecture. With proficiency in PHP (including Laravel and CakePHP), Python, Vue.js, and Tailwind CSS, I ensure the code I write is both understandable and maintainable. My strong communication and problem-solving skills ensure smooth collaboration and successful projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer, Brain Station 23 PLC

July 2022 - Present

- · Lead the design and implementation of scalable modules using microservice architecture.
- Analyze client needs and suggest tailored solutions.
- · Conduct code reviews and mentor junior developers.
- Foster a collaborative and motivated team environment.

Software Engineer, Brain Station 23 PLC

Jan,2020 - June,2022

- · Developed optimized code for new features.
- · Managed and optimized databases.
- Contributed to all stages of the development lifecycle.

Associate Software Engineer, Brain Station 23 PLC

Nov,2018 - Dec,2019

- Implemented change requests and extended features.
- Assisted in new feature development.
- · Engaged in R&D tasks.

PROJECTS

DYNAMIC WORKFLOW ENGINE

May, 2021 - Present

Client: Grameenphone Tele Company, Bangladesh

Role: Senior Software Engineer

Technology: Laravel, VueJs, AWS(s3), Docker, Microservice

Link: https://xpert-stage1.grameenphone.com:8098

Summary:

- Implemented microservice architecture and API Gateway from monolith architecture.
- Designed and implemented a custom central method-based authorization system.
- This project increased efficiency by 30%
- Developed a multi-vendor workflow engine with Laravel backend and Vue.js frontend.
- Led a team of two throughout the development process.

REGULATORY COMPLIANCE MANAGEMENT:

Sept, 2023 - Present

Client: Grameenphone Tele Company, Bangladesh **Technology**: Laravel, VueJs, AWS(s3), Docker, Monolith

Role: Technical Lead

Link: https://xpert-stage1.grameenphone.com:8099

Summary:

- · Worked as a technical lead
- Overall project is minimal but has very logical depth

- · Features included:
 - · Policy management
 - · Compliance monitoring
 - Risk assessment
 - Customized dashboard for CEO/CXO
 - Regulatory change management
- · It was very fun to work in this project.

BARD ERP:

Client: Bangladesh Academy Of Rural Development, Cumilla

Link: https://erp.bard.gov.bd/

Technology: Laravel, VueJs, AWS(s3), Docker, Monolith **Role**: Software Engineer - Senior Software Engineer

Summary:

This is a complete ERP solution made with laravel in modular monolith architectural design.

- I was involved in this project for more than 2 years.
- Designed and Implemented Accounting, Training, HRM, Vehicle Module
- · Feature enhancement & Assisted in other modules as well

Note: please email me for the user credentials if you need.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Language: PHP, Python, Javascript, C++

• Backend Framework: Laravel, CakePHP

• Frontend: Vanilla Js, Vue Js, Nuxt Js, Jquery, Tailwind css

Containerization: Docker
 Message Broker: RabbitMQ
 Cache: Redis, Memcached
 Version Control: GIT

PORTFOLIO

Please feel free to browse my portfolio to get a glimpse of all my pet projects and leetcode solutions.

Link: https://imran-hossain-16.netlify.app/

EDUCATION

Bachelor In Computer Science And Engineering

International Islamic University, Chittagong

January,2014 - March,2018

CGPA: 3.69 out of 4

ACHIEVEMENTS

- ACM ICPC Regional Participation, 2015
- Winner of inter university app contest, 2017 (Dhaka, Bangladesh)
- Co-author of nameGist: A phonetic Algorithm (Springer, 2019)
- Grameenphone Innovation Lab (Q4 Awards)
- Judge of liuc Inter university hackathon, 2020
- Certificate Link: Online Certificate
- Publication Link: nameGist: a novel phonetic algorithm with bilingual support | Request PDF

HOBBIES

- Playing Piano
- E-sports Tournaments
- Driving Cars

REFERENCE

- Mohammad Abdus Sattar
 - Software Engineer, StudyDrive Berlin, Germany, shohag.cse@hotmail.com

March 2019 - April 2021

- Rashid Al Shafee
 - Software Engineer(L-2), Kinetik Dhaka, Bangladesh, rashidodd@gmail.com